原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译：草草 木浅   小食人魔
翻译：小食人魔  CC   校对：木浅
时间轴：想念Gallifrey的wholock  Toozii
后期：斯人      总监：木浅
诉 讼 双 雄
第七季   第七集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
我建议我们两个
I'm talking about the both of us,
建议哈德曼两个厉害的初级合伙人
convincing Hardman that two kickass junior partners
比一个新高级合伙人要好
are worth as much as one new senior partner.
只要你愿意做小人
You had the chance to triple our business,
就能把我们的生意扩大两倍
and all you had to do was take a knee.
现在就告诉我  不是你
Tell me right now you weren't the one
把我的计划透露给了弗莱彻引擎公司
that Fletcher Engines my game plan.
哈德曼跟我说  他本来就没想让你做合伙人
Hardman told me he wasn't gonna make you partner anyway.
他把这个机会给我
And once he offered it to me,
-我只要  -出卖我
-all I had to do was... - Sell me out.
迈克的无偿服务案是针对一个监狱
Mike's pro bono is against some prison.
你猜是谁建的这些监狱
And guess who builds those prisons.
我向他保证过
I gave him my word.
你也曾经向我保证过
And you once gave your word to me
然后出尔反尔
and went back on it.
我不得不当面对他撒谎
I had to lie to Harvey's face.
你要么去法律诊所工作
You either go and work at the clinic
要么继续留在皮尔逊・斯佩克特
or you stay at Pearson Specter.
但你不能再像现在这样把两边都当傻瓜
But you can't play them both for fools
还让我来当你的挡箭牌
and put me in the middle.
我和他的诊所签了协议
I have a binding agreement signed by his legal clinic,
声称他们不会接受
stating that they would have no outside help
皮尔森-斯派克特-利特的帮助
from Pearson Specter Litt on this case.
但他们用了
Yet they did.
你说愈合心伤的唯一办法
You convinced me the only way to heal
就是避免让这种事发生在其他人身上
was to keep this from happening to someone else,
现在我一无所有了
and now I have nothing.
你这样做并非只是为了
This isn't just about you protecting
维护你委托人的利益
your client's interests.
而且是为了保护你自己
It's about you protecting yourself.
所以你还是把实话告诉我吧
Why don't you tell me what's really going on here?
就是这样
That's it.
他们此后一直以此要挟我
They've had me by the balls ever since.
天呐  你怎么会让自己陷入那样的境地
Jesus-- how'd you let yourself get compromised like that?
这是我的事  哈维
This is my situation, Harvey.
不  这是律所的事
No. This is a firm situation,
而且我们得跟那些混蛋撇清关系
and we need to cut ties with those bastards
马上就做
right the hell now.
难以置信
I don't believe this.
我向你坦白  你却拿官位压我
You're pulling rank after I opened up to you?
太扯了
That's bullshit.
不  亚历克斯
No, Alex.
扯淡的是你居然允许自己
What's bullshit is you letting yourself
五年来都处于这样的情况之中
be put in that position for the last five years.
-允许  -是的  允许
- Letting? - Yeah, letting.
现在我得帮我们解脱  因为你坑了我
And now I gotta get us out, because you did this to me.
既然我们要互相指责  哈维
Well, as long as we're throwing blame around, Harvey,
我才没坑你
I didn't do shit to you.
是你坑了我
You did this to me.
全押
All in.
这次别想  哥们
Not this time, brother.
我发现你了
I got you.
你发现个鬼
Bullshit, you got me.
七年前
我了解你的手法
I know how you play.
你看过才开牌  你至多就有个J加10
You checked to open. You got jack/ten at best.
你在唬人  我跟
This is a bluff. I'm calling.
随你的吧
Do what you have to do.
两个K一个7  混蛋
Kings over sevens, motherfu--er.
3个7  小家伙
Trip sevens, little man.
或许你终究不了解我的手法
Maybe you don't know how I play after all.
你情绪不对劲
You're on tilt.
一晚上都是
You've been on tilt all night.
刚刚那一手很蠢  你也清楚
That was a stupid play and you know it.
你怎么回事
What's going on with you?
我今天本该当上合伙人的
I was supposed to make partner today,
但路易・利特坑了我  就是这样
but Louis Litt screwed me over, so there.
所以我火大
That's why I'm pissed.
我去
Shit.
我不知道
I didn't know.
现在你知道了
Well, now you do.
我不明白  哈维
I don't understand, Harvey.
我以为你在那边是杰西卡・皮尔逊的人
I thought you were Jessica Pearson's guy over there.
我也以为  但她没有支持我
I thought so too, but she didn't have my back.
那要是我支持你呢
Well, what if I had your back?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我听汤米・布莱顿的意思
I heard Tommy Bratton talking.
他们打算招人进来
They're looking to bring someone in.
只要你开口  我肯定能让你做为合伙人进来
You say the word, I bet I can get you in as partner.
你有什么好处
What's in it for you?
布莱顿打算去邀请一个
Bratton's about to make an offer
斯卡登的挣钱好手
to some big-time earner at Skadden.
要我说  我们去
I say you and me go in there
跟他说  两个初级合伙人比一个
and tell him two junior partners are a hell of a lot better
高级合伙人要好
than one senior partner.
-算了  -得了  哈维
- Pass. - Come on, Harvey.
想想嘛
At least think about it.
我不需要想
I don't need to think about it.
我刚经历了这样的事
I just went through the same thing,
而提出提议的那人
and the guy who proposed it
最终背后给了我一刀
ended up stabbing me in the back.
我不会那么对你的
I wouldn't do that to you.
是啊  多谢你的提议  但是
Yeah, well, I appreciate your offer, but...
我不会给你机会的
I'm not going to give you the opportunity.
要我借你筹码吗
Now, you need me to stake you?
给你300
There's 300.
我听说法庭上的事了
I heard about what happened in court.
我知道你放弃了案子  迈克  我很遗憾
I know you gave up the case, Mike, I'm sorry.
瑞秋  我放弃了案子是因为你提醒我
Rachel, I gave the case up because you reminded me
要遵守承诺  但我说过了
to be a man of my word, but like I said,
我先承诺了奥斯卡・雷耶斯
I gave my word to Oscar Reyes first.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是我不想骗你
It means that I don't want to lie to you,
我也不想骗哈维  但是
and I don't want to lie to Harvey, but...
我会让这案子上刑事法庭
I'm going to get this case opened in criminal court,
而且这并不违反
and for the record, that does not violate
我签署的协议
the agreement that I signed.
那你会告诉哈维咯
So you're going to tell Harvey, right?
如果他问  我会说
If he asks me, I'll tell him,
但我不会主动说
but I'm not going to volunteer it,
而且我要知道你是否能接受
and I need to know if you're good with that.
-迈克  -你回答前
- Mike-- - Before you answer,
我要你想想
I want you to think about the fact
这些人在延长刑期
that these guys are extending sentences.
如果是我在里面
What if it were me in there,
是我的刑期被延长了呢
and it was my sentence that got extended?
我只有一个问题
I just have one question.
要是哈维问我呢
What if Harvey asks me about it?
那你说实话
Then you tell him the truth.
那好  我能接受
Then yeah, I'm good with it.
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
*See the money, wanna stay for your meal*
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
*Get another piece of pie for your wife*
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
*Everybody wanna know how it feel*
*所有人都想见见那景象*
*Everybody wanna see what it's like*
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
*I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind*
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
*Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money*
*好了*
*All right*
*退开点  我要跳舞*
*All step back, I'm 'bout to dance*
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
*The greenback boogie*
诉讼双雄 第七季 第七集
这是什么
What's this?
我还没为让我当上律师的事感谢你
I never thanked you for allowing me into the Bar,
我觉得比起果篮  你会更喜欢刑事案件
and I figured you'd prefer a criminal case to a fruit basket.
这是民事诉讼
This is a civil case.
原本是的
It was a civil case.
但不非得
But it doesn't have to be.
听上去不像礼物
That doesn't sound like a gift to me.
像是帮你忙
It sounds like a favor for you.
安妮塔  你说你看重做正确的事
Anita, you said you're about doing what's right.
有人为牟利而有意延长刑期
People are being kept in prison for money.
这是不对的
That's not right.
即便真是如此
If that's true.
我很希望我能做点什么  但我做不了
I wish there was something I could do about it, but I can't.
什么意思
What do you mean, you can't?
你明白的
You know what I mean.
没有人会希望我花时间
Nobody wants to see me spending my time
帮助坏人出狱
getting bad guys out of prison.
那如果我告诉你这是两家财富500强
And what if I told you it was a criminal conspiracy
公司之间的犯罪阴谋呢
between two Fortune 500 companies?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我无法追查这件案子是因为
I couldn't pursue the case because we represent
另一位委托人向我们施压  要我们放弃
another client who was pressuring me to drop it,
他们那么做
and there's no way they did that
绝不会单纯为保护改造公司  他们也有份
just to protect Reform Corp., which means they're in on it.
你有证据吗
Do you have any proof?
没有  但是
No, but--
你给我拿来阴谋的证据  我就追查
You bring me some proof of a conspiracy and I'll pursue it.
我只能做到这里了
That's the best I can do.
安妮塔  我没有资源去
Anita, I don't have the resources to--
不关我的事
Not my problem.
还有
And another thing...
不关你拿来什么  必须是关于改造公司的
Whatever you do bring me has to be on the Reform Corp.
与协议无关  否则
Side of the arrangement, because if it isn't,
你就打破了保密协议  我也没法用
you're breaking privilege, and I can't use any of it.
哈维
Harvey.
我有事要告诉你  但我得知道
There's something I want to tell you, but I need to know
你是否已经放下了路易和升职的事
if you're over what happened with Louis and the promotion.
我没事  唐娜
I'm fine, Donna.
那好  因为我明早得早点下班
Good, because I need to leave work early tomorrow night.
干什么
What for?
是我跟马克的六个月纪念
It's my six-month anniversary with Mark.
-这个表情干吗  -没事
- What's that face? - Nothing.
我大概只是没想到你也是那样的人
I guess I just didn't think you were one of those people.
什么样的人
What people?
就是会庆祝
The people that celebrate
侄女三年级毕业
their niece's third-grade graduation
当做像登月一般隆重的人
like it was the Moon landing.
你上次跟谁
And when was the last time
认真约会六个月是什么时候了
you saw anyone seriously for six months?
我不是这谈话的话题
I'm not the topic of this conversation.
你怎么能是呢
How could you be?
因为我们在说
Because we're talking about
成熟投入的感情关系
a mature and committed relationship.
你说得对  唐娜  是这样
You're right, Donna, we are,
所以  我有份礼物给你庆祝纪念日
which is why I got you a gift to celebrate your anniversary.
哈维
Harvey...
这很慷慨  但我不能要
this is very generous, but I can't accept it.
为什么不
Why not?
因为马克为我们计划了特别一晚
Because Mark planned a special night for us,
等我拿出一张礼品卡来支付时
and how's he going to feel when I pull out a gift card
他会怎么想啊
to help pay for it?
-我不是那意思  -我知道
- That wasn't the idea. - I know,
但如果你真想给我礼物
but if you want to really give me a gift,
答应我  你一晚上都不会打来  或打断我
promise you won't call or interrupt me the entire night.
我保证
I promise.
谢谢  哈维
Thanks, Harvey.
该死  杰弗里  这可是工作场所
God damn it, Jeffrey, this is a place of business,
不是宠物动物园  你要么把金鱼冲下下水道
not a petting zoo, so you either flush the goldfish
要么就等着被炒吧
or you're fired.
你没有那个权力
You don't have the authority to do that.
章程207节  第三段
Section 207, paragraph three of the by-laws:
不服合伙人命令可以解雇
Insubordination to a partner results in termination.
这跟我的鱼毫无关系  你也清楚
This has nothing to do with my fish and you know it.
当然就是为了你的鱼
It's got everything to do with that fish,
你别再顶嘴了
and I don't want to hear another word about it,
所以除非你想再...
so unless you want to say another word--
路易  能谈谈吗
Louis, can I talk to you for a second?
杰西卡  我正在...
Hey, Jessica, I was just in the middle of something--
马上
Now.
-怎么  -你在干什么
- Yes? - What the hell do you think you're doing?
我在对那个讨厌鬼
I'm exercising my authority
行使我合伙人的权力
as junior partner over that douche.
通过弄死他的鱼吗
By trying to kill his fish?
不  通过努力保持这里的秩序
No, by trying to keep order in the bullpen.
杰西卡  杰弗里的工作习惯
Jessica, Jeffrey's work habits are--
是因为我没有叫他初级合伙人
It's because I didn't call him junior partner.
闭嘴  这和我对他
Shut up, this has nothing to do
那条愚蠢无礼的鱼的看法
with how I feel about his stupid,
没有半点关系
disrespectful asshole fish.
路易...
Louis...
你想过看心理医生吗
have you considered therapy?
我干嘛要那么做
Why would I do that?
那就像是让巴雷什尼科夫上舞蹈课一样
That would be like Baryshnikov taking dance lessons.
20世纪最出色的舞蹈家之一
-路易  -杰西卡
- Louis-- - Jessica,
软蛋才会退缩
shrinks are for pussies.
现在  我能回去继续教训杰弗里吗
Now, can I go back to yelling at Jeffrey?
这些助理需指导和教训
Because these associates need guidance and discipline.
听我说  路易
Listen to me, Louis.
你和哈维的事我之所以置身事外
I stayed out of that whole thing between you and Harvey
是因为这是丹尼尔的决定
because that was Daniel's call.
你想欺负初级律师  我不管你
And you want to go off on the associates, that's one thing,
但如果你拿这次升职太当回事
but you let this promotion go to your head,
而拿哈维出气的话
and you take it out on Harvey,
我就不会置身事外了
I'm going to step the hell back in.
杰西卡  作为初级合伙人我向你保证
Jessica, you have my word as junior partner:
哈维出了什么问题
if there's any problem with Harvey,
都不会是我惹的
it won't be because of me.
我现在忙着呢
I'm a little busy right now.
不管你忙什么  都放放再说
Well, whatever it is, put it to the side.
丹尼尔想让你和路易一起处理
Daniel wants you to work with Louis
莱因斯多夫的案子
on the Reinsdorf case.
你有什么话  就直说吧
You got something to say, Harvey, say it.
好  那我就说了
Okay, I'll say it.
哈德曼搞我时你并没站我这边
You didn't have my back when Hardman screwed me over,
现在他想羞辱我
and now you're carrying his water
你还帮着他
while he tries to humiliate me.
我不管他想干嘛
I don't care what he's doing.
我在乎的是我做的事  就是看你能不能
I care about what I'm doing, which is to see if you can
放下你的自尊  往长远了看
put that ego of yours aside and play the long game.
你什么意思
What the hell are you talking about?
我知道有多少次查尔斯・范・戴克
Do you have any idea how many times I had to smile
把他的工作扔给我时我得笑脸相陪
and take it when Charles Van Dyke pawned his work off on me?
当斯坦利・戈登把我叫到他办公室
Or when Stanley Gordon would call me into his office
只是为了我离开时能视奸我的屁股
just so he could ogle my ass when I left?
这不是一回事
That is not the same thing.
更别提施密特像活在20世纪50年代那样
Not to mention when Schmidt would talk about "The blacks"
谈论黑人
like he was living in 1950.
我忍辱负重这么多年  哈维
I sucked it up for years, Harvey.
现在轮到你了
Now it's your turn.
如果我忍不了呢
What if I won't?
那你我不是一伙人  因为如果你连
Then you're not my guy, because if you can't even
假装向对手服软都不会
pretend to bend a knee to your rivals,
那无论日后你通过做什么试图超越他们
it doesn't matter what you do to get ahead of them in the future.
因为他们在一英里外就会发现你
They're going to see you coming a mile away.
克鲁格先生  多谢你能见我
Mr. Kreuger, I appreciate you meeting me.
这里又不是唐顿庄园  哈维
This isn't Downton Abbey, Harvey.
这是个建筑公司
It's a construction firm.
叫我派特  随意点
Call me Pat, or see yourself out.
那好吧  派特
Fair enough, Pat.
我想你知道我们律所一个初级合伙人
I'm sure you know that a junior partner at our firm
违背了约定
broke his word.
我想应该表示下歉意
I think you're owed an apology.
通常都是客户付钱给律师
Usually the clients pay the lawyers,
而不是反过来
not the other way around.
现在是非常情况
This is a unique situation.
这笔钱数目太大  看起来像贿赂了
This looks a lot like you're trying to pay me off.
我只是想改变错误  让你能继续自己的事
I'm trying to make things right, and allow you to move on.
你想知道如何得到别人鼎力支持吗  哈维
You want to know how to get someone's best effort, Harvey?
不是给他们一大笔钱
It's not paying them the most money.
而是要保证你们之间
It's making sure that their interests
有共同的利益
are aligned with yours,
亚历克斯・威廉姆斯和我一样都想了结此案
and Alex Williams wants this case to go away as much as I do.
你不用把自己利益和别人绑在一起
You don't need your interests aligned anymore.
这案子结束了
This case is over.
或许是  或许不是
Maybe it is. And maybe it isn't.
但我听说过你们律所有类似的事
But I've heard that from your firm once before.
我记得是你自己的律师
And then I believe it was your own associate
先对案子提起重审的
who opened the case again in the first place.
所以  你看  哈维
So, you see, Harvey,
此事利益不仅牵涉到
it's not just Alex's interests
亚历克斯和我  还包括你的
that are aligned with mine. It's yours.
我觉得这样挺好的
And I plan to keep it that way.
我猜猜  你是来核查我的证词的
Let me guess: you're here to go over my testimony.
我告诉过你除非我女儿拿到了钱
I already told you I'm not giving you anything
否则我什么也不会说
until my daughter gets paid.
我不是为这个来的  弗兰克
It's not what I'm here for, Frank.
我得知道你知不知道
I need to know if you know
改造公司跟外面有什么阴谋
anything about a conspiracy outside of Reform Corp.
改造公司外面...
Conspiracy outside of R--
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
这是怎么回事
What the hell's going on here?
我们的案子被驳回了
We got thrown off the case.
你刚才说什么
What did you just say to me?
-弗兰克  -你之前来
- Frank-- - 'Cause you came in here
承诺要给我女儿个未来
promising my daughter a future.
现在你告诉我这都是废话
Now you're telling me it's all a bunch of shit.
这不是废话
It's not a bunch of shit,
我能让案子重审
and I can get the case reopened,
但我得掌握马斯特森建筑公司
but I need evidence of a conspiracy
阴谋的相关证据
with Masterson Construction.
那我帮不了你  因为据我所知
Then I can't help you, 'cause all I know is,
就是这些人给我们安排的工作
those are the guys that put us all to work.
工作
Work?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
这些地方可不像丹伯里
Those places aren't like Danbury.
我们拼命的给他们建造监狱
We work our asses off to build their prison
能让他们多关些像我们这种人
so they can put more of us away.
但如果你想找什么阴谋  那没有
But if you're looking for a conspiracy, there's not.
这件事是公开的  名曰"能力重建"
They do it all out in the open, call it "Rehabilitation."
这件事或许没猫腻  但别的肯定有
Well, it may not have been hidden, but something is.
我觉得你帮我指明了正确方向
And I think you just pointed me in the right direction.
你都干了什么
What the hell did you do?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你背着我去找马斯特森
You went to Masterson behind my back.
我之前告诉你我得怎么做
I did what I told you I was going to do.
我把你弄进的烂摊子  我要把你弄出来
I got you into this mess, I'm going to get you out.
去找马斯特森
Then all going to Masterson does
就是让自己成为他们的目标
is put you in their crosshairs.
我早就是他们的目标了
I'm already in their crosshairs.
既然我知道什么情况
And now that I know what happened,
我也就是其中一份子了
I might as well have been a part of it myself.
我们该把真相告诉迈克・罗斯
Then maybe instead of poking the bear,
而不是去招惹一头熊
we should tell Mike Ross the truth.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我们都清楚除非案子结束
We both know that Mike is not going to let this thing go
否则迈克不会置之不顾的
till he gets to the bottom of it.
也许  如果我坦白一切
Maybe, if I just come clean--
听我说  亚历克斯
Listen to me, Alex.
你去把你的事告诉他
You go to him with your story,
你就是在帮他把事情理清楚
you're going to give him a map to what happened,
那是一罐汽油  加一根火柴
a can of gas, and a match
让他去把一切都点了
to light the whole damn thing on fire.
希望你是对的  哈维  因为我还有个女儿
I hope you're right, Harvey, because I've got a daughter,
如果我不趁有机会就把事情摆平
and if I didn't take a chance to stop this thing when I had it...
听我说  亚历克斯  你别管了
I'm telling you, Alex, you let it go.
-哈维  -路易
- Harvey. - Louis.
杰西卡说哈德曼想让我们
Jessica said Hardman wants us to work
一起处理莱因斯多夫的案子
on the Reinsdorf case together.
她跟我也这么说
She said the same thing to me.
我是来帮忙的  不是来吵架的
Well, I'm here to help, not get in a fight.
我也这么想
My feelings exactly.
很好  我觉得我们可以先讨论下战术
Good, I thought we could start by talking strategy.
等等  你是首席吗
I'm sorry, but are you first chair?
不  你是  但是我觉得
No, you are, but I just thought--
你想法并不重要
Doesn't matter what you thought,
因为我们的战术就是向他们的法务长下手
because our strategy is to go after their general counsel.
你打算何时罢免这家伙
And when would you like to depose this guy?
不  我要让这混蛋上法庭
Never, because I'm going to put that asshole on the stand,
然后把他像逾越节的面包一样撕碎
and I'm going to crack him like a piece of matzo on Passover.
路易  你不罢免他而让他直接上庭
Louis, you put him on the stand without deposing him,
你得问些你连答案都不知道的问题
you'll be asking questions you don't know the answers to.
-那又怎么了  -那
- So what? - So,
这是律师从业的第一守则
that's the number one rule of lawyering.
多谢提醒  F.李・贝雷
Well, thank you, F. Lee Bailey.
O.J.辛普森的律师
我觉得这的第一守则
And here I thought the number one rule
是知道你自己的位置
was to know your goddamn place.
我不需要一个六年律师给的建议
And I don't need to take advice from a sixth-year associate.
我不想因为你不听劝
And I don't need to take a loss on my record
害我全胜记录被打破
because you're too insecure to listen to reason.
你知道吗  哈维  你什么也不用做
You know what, Harvey, you don't need to take anything
因为本案不归你管
because you're not in charge.
所以你决定吧  你是上庭
So it's up to you: you gonna get on board
还是回家找妈妈抱抱
or are you gonna go crying to mama?
你说得对  路易  你是合伙人
You're right, Louis. You're the partner.
你是来支持你的
I'm just here to back you up.
唐娜  我想让你放下手头的工作
Donna, I want you to pull whatever strings you have to
把莱因斯多夫的案子提到明天
to get the Reinsdorf trial moved up to tomorrow.
我这就去
I'll get right on it.
还有  别告诉路易
And one more thing: don't tell Louis.
什么  哈维
What? Harvey,
杰西卡说言归于好
Jessica said to bury the hatchet,
不是背后给路易捅刀子
not stick it in Louis's back.
唐娜  我带着一片好意去他办公室
Donna, I went into his office in good faith
他用了不到30秒
and it took him less than 30 seconds
就拿头衔来压我
to wave his title in my face.
这和你把你的自尊至于公司利益之上
What does that have to do with putting
有什么关系
the firm's interest above your ego?
因为  当我对他的战术提出合理问题时
Because, when I brought up a legitimate issue with his strategy,
他不分青红皂白
he shot me down for no other reason
立刻就让我闭嘴
than it came out of my mouth.
我告诉你  我们不这么做  就得输了
I'm telling you: we don't do this, we're going to lose.
看着我
Look at me.
你确定这样做是正确的吗
Are you sure this is the right call?
听我说
Listen to me.
杰西卡让我把目光放长远  我正是这么做的
Jessica wants me to play the long game, and that's what I'm doing.
我坐在那儿装怂  他当真了
I sat in there, ate shit, and he bought it.
所以  明天我要赢下这个案子
So now, tomorrow, I'm going to win this thing,
杰西卡就知道她可以指望我了
and Jessica's going to know she can count on me.
好吧
All right.
我来提前庭审日期
I'll move the court date,
并且确保路易不会知道这件事
and I'll make sure Louis doesn't find out.
很好  哈维  你过来了
Harvey, good, you're here.
我们没机会谈谈你  亚历克斯  还有迈克之间
We didn't get a chance to talk about what happened
发生了什么
with you, Alex, and Mike.
确实如此  实际上
No, we didn't, and as a matter of fact,
我在想迈克在哪儿
I'm wondering where Mike is.
他之前在这儿  然后走了
Well, he was in earlier, but then he left.
但我猜你并不是真的
But I'm guessing that's not really
要问这个
the question you're asking.
你想知道他是不是还在管那个案子
You want to know if he's somehow still pursing that case.
如果确实是这样呢
And what if I do?
从我的个人经验来看
I would say from personal experience,
先做好心理准备  能接受答案再提问题
don't ask a question unless you're really ready to hear the answer.
你到底以为自己在干什么
What the hell do you think you're doing?
杰西卡  你怎么会知道
Jessica, how did you know?
这不是重点
It doesn't matter how.
重点在于  我让你和路易一起负责这个案子
What matters is, I told you to work it out with Louis,
而路易现在坐在办公室里
and right now, he's sitting in his office
根本不知道案子开庭了
with no idea this case is starting.
就像你说的  我在打持久战
Exactly, I'm playing the long game, like you said.
不  哈维
No, Harvey.
你什么都别想打了
You're not playing anything,
因为这个案子是我的了
because this case is mine now.
-什么  -你已经听见了
- What? - You heard me.
我给你下达了直接命令
I gave you a direct order,
而你根本没拿我当回事
and you spat in my face.
这太扯了  杰西卡
Jessica, this is bullshit.
我去跟路易谈话  可他直接羞辱我
I went in there and he spat in my face,
这点我可以忍  但我忍不了的是
and I was willing to take it, but what I'm not willing to take
因为内部泄愤而输掉案子
is losing this thing out of spite,
要是你现在接受这个案子
and if you take this case right now,
你肯定会输的
you're going to lose,
因为你根本不知道现在是怎么回事
because you have no idea what's going on with it.
我可能输也可能赢
Maybe I will and maybe I won't.
但有时候也得让老将坐回替补席
But sometimes you have to bench your quarterback
好显示谁才是团队的管理者
to show 'em who's running the team,
不管这样做会不会有损失
whether you take a loss or not.
全体起立
All rise!
时间到了  哈维  你该退后了
Time's up, Harvey. Step aside.
杰西卡  别在公众场合对我这样
Jessica, please don't do this to me in public.
这不是我对你怎么样
I'm not doing anything to you.
是你自找的
You did this to yourself.
律师  有问题吗
Do we have a problem, counselor?
没有  法官大人
No, Your Honor, we don't.
事务所需要我的这位同事回去处理些事情
My colleague is needed back at our firm.
由我来负责
I'm stepping in.
既然如此  全体请坐
In that case, be seated, everyone.
现在开庭
Court is now in session.
迈克尔  你为什么关门
Michael, why are you closing the door?
你知道门一关我就不舒服
You know I'm uncomfortable with obstructed exits.
因为我要让你做件事
Because I need to ask you something,
中途不希望被打扰
and I don't want to be interrupted.
迈克尔  你这是要我黑进政府机构
Michael, you're asking me to hack a government institution.
我不能这么干
I can't do that.
看仔细点  本杰明
Look closely, Benjamin.
这是一家私人机构  而且要我说
It's a private corporation, and I'm telling you,
他们是一群混蛋
they're scumbags.
哪个案子需要这样做
What's it for?
什么意思
What do you mean?
如果你要我做这种事
I mean, if you're asking me to do something like this,
我得把它归到某个案子里面
I have to bill it to a case.
要是我叫你不要归到案子里呢
And what if I asked you not to?
那我要问你为什么
I would have to ask you why.
我我要违抗哈维的意愿
I'm going against Harvey's wishes.
以前你也要我这样做过
You asked me to do that once before
是为了一个模拟审判
for a mock trial.
我要知道  这次是模拟审判  还是真格的
And I need to know, is this mock, or is it real?
这次是真的
It's real,
而且不能让哈维知道
and Harvey can't know.
哈维  我以为你不会到坚尼街南边来[社区相对贫穷]
Harvey, I didn't think you ever got south of Canal Street.
今天算是破例了
Yeah, well, today I'm making an exception.
你的邀约还有效吗
Is that offer still on the table?
你是认真的吗
Are you serious?
我都过来了  对吧
I'm here, aren't I?
那当然了  还有效
Then hell yeah, it's still on the table.
我这就去找汤米・布莱顿谈话
I'll talk to Tommy Bratton right now.
你跟他谈话的时候
Well, when you talk to him,
顺便告诉他  他答应我的条件  我才会来
you tell him I'm only coming over if he meets my demands.
什么条件
And what demands would those be?
我不仅要当合伙人  我要一间风景优美的办公室
I don't just want partner. I want an office with a view.
我赢的案子  钱都归我
I want to eat what I kill and I want to get paid
而且我要比事务所的其他初级合伙人挣得多
more than any other junior partner in the firm.
你这要求可不低
Those are some pretty big asks.
我不能保证布莱顿会答应
I can't guarantee Bratton's going to say yes.
要是你想让我帮你当合伙人  就设法让他答应吧
You want to make partner on my coattails, you make him say yes.
让你帮我  我们现在说的是互相帮助
Your coattails? I'm talking about me helping you
我也没少帮你
as much as about you helping me.
那你就做好约定过的事
Then do what you said you were going to do,
因为如果不这样
because if you can't make that happen,
他们就不会尊重我  而我不想去一个
they don't respect me, and I'm not coming to a place
不受尊重的地方
where I'm not respected.
好吧  哈维  但如果你想被人尊重
Okay, Harvey, but if you want respect,
你也要尊重别人
you need to show some damn respect.
我去为你做担保
I go in to stick my neck out for you,
你可别说你还要考虑考虑
you don't come back and say you'll consider it.
成交
It's a done goddamn deal.
好  亚历克斯  我向你保证
Okay, Alex, you have my word.
你让他满足我的条件
You get me everything I'm asking for...
我就跟皮尔逊-哈德曼一刀两断
I'm done with Pearson Hardman.
杰西卡  你好
Jessica. Hey, how are ya?
路易  还记得我们谈过
Louis, remember when we talked about
不要对哈维滥用权力吧
not abusing your power with Harvey?
当然  所以我对他格外尊重
Absolutely, and that's why I treated him with the utmost respect.
如果是这样
Well, if that's the case,
他为什么要瞒着你为莱因斯多夫出庭
then exactly why did he litigate Reinsdorf behind your back?
妈的  他干什么了
Goddamn it. What the hell did he do?
我不关心他做了什么
I'm not concerned with what he did.
我关心的是你做了什么
I'm concerned with what you did.
杰西卡  我发誓自己完完全全是个绅士
Jessica, I swear, I was the perfect gentleman,
但是哈维质疑我的领导能力
but then Harvey questioned my leadership.
换句话说  他有更好的想法吗
In other words, he had a better idea than you?
不管他的想法是不是更好
Well, whether it was or it wasn't,
他不尊重初级合伙人这一位置
he didn't respect the office of junior partner.
本来就没有"初级合伙人这一位置"  路易
Because there is no office of junior partner, Louis,
问题的关键不是哈维
and the real problem here isn't Harvey.
而是你的态度总是气势汹汹
It's that chip on your shoulder.
什么汹汹
What chip?
路易  我要你明早九点
Louis, I need you to be at this address
按照地址去这里
tomorrow morning at 9:00 a.M.
-为什么  -因为我相信心理咨询会让你好些
- Why? - Because I believe you will benefit from therapy,
而这个人是最好的心理医生
and this man is the best in the business.
等等
Back the truck up.
杰西卡  你说心理治疗吗
Jessica, therapy?
我是你见过的心态最稳定的人了
I'm the most stable, secure man you ever met.
你要是和我争这一点
And you fight me on this,
你就要失去这份工作了
you'll be the most unemployed man I've ever met.
听明白了吗
Do we understand each other?
好  早上九点
Yeah. 9:00 a.M. It is.
还有  路易
And Louis,
你踏进门的那一刻
when you walk through that door,
就会有种强烈的想要扭头就走的冲动
you're going to be tempted to turn right the hell around,
让我告诉你  你要是还想在这儿干下去
and I'm telling you, if you want a future here,
就别那么干
you won't.
哈维  你怎么在这儿
Harvey, what are you doing here?
我以为你一整天都会在法庭上
I thought you were in court all day.
杰西卡有其他打算
Well, Jessica had other plans,
比如说把我从这个案子撵走
like booting me off this case.
什么
What?
她走进来把我撵走了
She walked in there and threw me out
让我夹着尾巴做人
with my tail between my legs,
好像我是个一文不值的一年律师
like I was a piece-of-shit first-year associate.
听我说  你要冷静一下  我们才能想想
Listen to me, you need to calm down so we can figure out
现在要怎么办
what we're going to do.
我很冷静
I am calm,
而且我已经留好后路了
and I already took care of what we're going to do.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
我在布莱顿・古尔德给我们找了份工作
I got us an offer at Bratton Gould.
如果事情发展如我所料
If everything goes like I think,
我们这周结束之前就能过去了
we'll be there by the end of the week.
什么
What?
这说不通
Harvey, that doesn't make any sense.
杰西卡最喜欢你了
Jessica's your biggest fan.
她一直都是支持你的
She's always been in your corner.
哈德曼提拔路易的时候  怎么没见她支持我
Was she in my corner when Hardman promoted Louis?
这么说不公平  那是由他决定的
That's not fair. That was his call.
今天在法庭所有人面前把我撵走
Well, whose call was cutting my balls off
又是由谁决定的
in front of the entire courtroom today?
我不管她说了什么
I don't care what she did.
那个女人自掏腰包
The woman paid for you to go to law school
供你念了法学院
out of her own pocket.
你做这种事之前
The least you can do is talk to her
起码你要跟她谈谈
before you do something like this.
唐娜  我试过和她谈
Donna, I tried talking to her.
但这不重要  已经太迟了
But it doesn't matter. It's too late.
我向亚历克斯保证过  这事不能撤销
I gave Alex my word. It's a done deal.
对你来说或许如此
Well, it may be a done deal for you,
但对我来说不是这样
but it isn't a done deal for me.
-唐娜  -我喜欢这里  哈维
- Donna-- - I like it here, Harvey,
而且你不能都不通知我一声  就这样做出
and you can't just make this kind of decision about my life
关乎我人生的决定
without running it by me first.
如果你是想用这种方法来让我留下
If this is your way of trying to get me to stay...
我无意逼迫你
I'm not trying to get you to do anything,
但我不会在还没跟你谈清楚前
but I'm not just gonna follow you out the door
就跟着你离开这里
without thinking this through.
唐娜  你想要什么  道歉吗
What do you want, Donna? You want an apology?
那好  对不起  我没有事先与你商量
Well, here it is: I'm sorry I didn't consult with you.
我不想听对不起
I don't want an apology, Harvey.
我想能事先和你谈谈以便把事情捋清楚
I wanted to talk this thing through with you,
而且这也正是你应该事先和杰西卡做的事
which, by the way, is what you should have done with Jessica.
我告诉你  唐娜
Well, you know what, Donna?
我不是来向你征求意见的
I didn't come to you for advice.
我是来通知你收拾东西走人的
I came to tell you to start packing.
但如果你不想跟我离开
But if you don't want to come with me,
那就别跟
then don't come with me.
瑞秋  有时间吗
Rachel, do you have a second?
当然
Of course.
迈克是为我进监狱的
Mike went to prison for me.
我欠他的  我知道
I owe him, and I know it.
但他不是我唯一有所亏欠的人
But he's not the only guy I owe,
如果如果我不闻不问
and that guy's going to have a serious problem
假装迈克不是我了解的那种人
if I stick my head in the sand,
我亏欠的另一个人就要陷入大麻烦了
pretending Mike isn't who I know he really is.
这种境地确实两难
That's a shitty situation to be in.
对  所以我准备问你一些事情
Yeah, it is, so I'm going to ask you something,
但我需要你诚实回答我
but I need you to be honest with me.
迈克还在处理起诉改造公司的那个案子吗
Is Mike still working on the case against Reform Corp.?
是的  哈维  而且我该告诉你
He is. And for the record, Harvey,
是他告诉我如果你问起
he told me that if you asked,
就把你想知道的事毫无保留地告诉你
to tell you everything you wanted to know.
他现在具体在做什么
What exactly is he doing?
他正在整理刑事案卷
He's trying to build a criminal case
以便交给安妮塔・吉布斯
to give to Anita Gibbs,
他有权这么做
which he has every right to do.
因为在他所签的协议上
Because the agreement he signed
明文禁止的只是民事诉讼
only precluded a civil suit.
没错
Exactly.
他处理到什么程度了
How far along is he?
我不知道  但按我对他的了解
I don't know, but knowing Mike,
相比今早  他肯定
I'm sure he's a hell of a lot closer
离胜利又近了一大步
than he was this morning.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
你想不想点瓶玫瑰葡萄酒
Do you want to share a bottle of rosé?
我还记得上次我们点了之后
I think I remember what happened the last time
发生的事
we did that.
那就更要点了
All the more reason to get it, then.
我很同意
I couldn't agree more.
既然已经点好了
Good, now that that is decided...
周年纪念日快乐
Happy anniversary.
莎士比亚的十四行诗
Shakespeare's sonnets.
人人都在谈论他
Everyone is talking about this guy.
显然他现在正当大热
Apparently he's all the rage right now.
这是我大学时最喜欢的课
This was my favorite class in college.
你是怎么知道的
How did you know?
我做了功课
I do my homework.
谢谢
Thank you.
-怎么了  -没什么
- What? - Nothing.
和一个听不懂话的男人
It's just so nice to be with a man
工作一整天后  能和如此体贴的男人
who's so thoughtful after spending all day with a man
共度时光真是太好了
who doesn't even know what the word means.
是指哈维
Talking about Harvey.
他要离开律所
He's leaving the firm,
他想当然地认为我会跟他走
and he just assumed that I would go with him.
他甚至没有先跟我商量
He didn't even think to ask me first.
今晚是庆祝之夜
We're celebrating tonight.
我们别聊哈维了
Let's not talk about Harvey.
我不是在聊哈维  我是在聊我的人生
I'm not talking about Harvey; I'm talking about my life,
以及我被迫要作出的一项重大决定
and a huge decision that I have to make.
-慢着  -你真的在考虑跟他离开吗
- Wait a second--you're actually thinking about going with him?
哪怕他如此对你
Even after the way he treated you?
我不知道我要怎么做
I don't know what I'm going to do.
如果我说我希望你留在
Well, what if I said that I'd like you to stay
皮尔逊・哈德曼呢
at Pearson Hardman?
-为什么这样说  -你知道为什么
- Why would you say that? - You know why.
因为在我们的关系中哈维如同静默的第三者
Because Harvey's like a silent partner in our relationship.
我们甚至无法在他的名字不出现
I mean, we can't even get through a dinner
的情况下好好享用晚餐
without his name coming up.
马克  我特别交待过他今晚别打扰我们
Mark, I specifically told him not to interrupt us tonight
所以他不会出现
so he wouldn't come up.
但他会以其他方式出现
And yet he came up anyway.
-马克  -听着
- Mark-- - Look,
我不会假装自己像你那么有洞察力
I don't pretend to be as insightful as you are,
但如果他要求你离开你热爱的工作
but if you can't even separate yourself from him
你却仍无法离开他
when he's asking you to leave a job that you love...
我只能好奇你到底是否真的热爱这份工作
makes me wonder if it's really the job you love after all.
你想让我说什么  马克
What do you want me to say, Mark?
我希望你说从今往后你不会
I want you to say that you're not going to follow the guy
只要他去哪儿你就跟着去哪儿
wherever he goes for the rest of your life.
我不会这么说的
I'm not going to say that.
好吧  那我想我是得到答案了
Okay, well, I guess I have my answer, then.
瑞秋  你不会相信...
Rachel, you are not going to believe--
迈克  在你说话之前
Mike, before you say anything...
哈维问我你是否仍在跟改造公司那个案子
Harvey asked me if you were still going after Reform Corp.,
我告诉他  是的
and I told him that you were.
没关系  因为我赢定了
Doesn't matter, 'cause I got 'em.
什么
What?
加洛告诉我马斯特森过去一直利用改造公司的囚犯
Gallo told me that Masterson was using Reform Corp.'s inmates
建造新监狱
to build new prisons.
私营企业使用囚犯是违法的
Okay, but using inmates for private companies is illegal.
本来是  但五年前
It would be, except five years ago,
亚历克斯・威廉姆斯从州惩教中心当局
Alex Williams got a waiver from the state corrections board
拿到了放弃书  允许他们用囚犯增补劳动力
allowing them to supplement their workforce with inmates.
那为什么是犯罪
So where's the crime?
慢着  为什么马斯特森的预算表
Wait a second. Why are Masterson's budgets
出现在改造公司的电子邮件服务器
on Reform Corp.'s email server?
更重要的是  为什么工人薪水
More importantly, why are the labor costs
只占了他们向本州申报的五分之一
1/5 of what they submitted to the state?
天呐
Jesus.
迈克  他们不仅仅是在用囚犯充补劳动力
Mike, they didn't just use the inmates to supplement the workforce;
而是工人本身就是囚犯
the inmates were the workforce.
也就是说改造公司不只是延长刑期
Which means Reform Corp.'s not just extending sentences,
他们欺骗了州政府
they're defrauding the state,
而且他们还与马斯特森把利润五五分
and they're splitting the profits with Masterson, 50/50.
迈克  你是从哪里拿到这些资料的
Mike, where did you get all this?
这重要吗
What does that matter?
很重要  因为如果这是从马斯特森流出的
It matters because if it came from Masterson,
那哈维能防止安妮塔・吉布斯用这资料
then Harvey can stop Anita Gibbs from using it.
这不是
Well, it didn't.
而是本杰明从改造公司的服务器上查到的
Benjamin got it from Reform Corp.'s server,
我们能整理马斯特森的资料然后交给吉布斯
which means we can redact Masterson, give it to Gibbs,
然后她就可以自己把各种资料整合起来
and she can put the pieces together herself.
哈维对此无能为力
There is nothing that Harvey can do about it.
迈克  他可能会因此而解雇你
Mike, he could fire you for this.
瑞秋  记忆中我如同被撕成两半
Rachel, I've been torn up trying to reconcile
痛苦地试图调和这两个不同的自己
two parts of myself for as long as I can remember:
无偿服务对公司法
pro bono versus corporate law.
如果他想解雇我  那就让他解雇吧
If he lets me go, then he lets me go.
你好
Hello?
我是路易・利特
I'm Louis Litt,
预约了9点来这里的
here for my 9:00 A.M. appointment.
有人吗
Hello?
你好  利特先生
Hi, ya, Mr. Litt.
我们一直在等你
We've been expecting you.
不好意思  你这是德国口音吗
I'm sorry, but did you just speak in a German accent?
请入坐
Please, taken ze seat.
我的天  你这个该死的纳粹
Holy shit, you're a goddamn Nazi.
你刚说什么
What did you just say to me?
我说就是跟你聊天气
I said I'm not going to sit here
我都不愿意  更别说向你敞开心扉了
and talk to you about the weather, let alone my goddamn feelings.
谢谢  但我不用了  维也纳炸牛排
Thanks, but no thanks, wiener schnitzel.
别这样  路易
Please, Louis.
给我两分钟
Just give me two minutes.
就两分钟
Two minutes.
首先...
First of all...
我想你是犹太人吧
I take it you're Jewish?
对  但现在回答这个问题会让我不舒服
Yeah, I'm not comfortable answering that right now.
好吧  显而易见
Well, it seems very clear,
鉴于你刚刚称我为纳粹
based on the fact that you just called me a Nazi.
你想说的是什么
What's your point?
如果我说我也是犹太人你会对此感兴趣吗
Would it interest you to know that I'm Jewish too?
拿出你的割礼证据
Yeah, well, take out your circumcised junk,
也许我就会相信你
and maybe I'll believe you.
我不打算这么做  路易
I'm not going to do that, Louis.
但我想说我的父母
But I will tell you that my parents
在二战期间还只是孩子
were both children during the war.
他们为了报名逃出了祖国  后来感到回归祖国
They survived by fleeing the country and felt it their duty
并且把我和我姐姐抚养成自豪的
to eventually return and raise both my sister and myself
德国人兼犹太人是他们的责任
as proud Germans and Jews.
所以如果你是因为
So, if you want to leave
不喜欢我的口音而打算离开
because you don't like the way I speak,
我能理解  但如果不是
I understand, but if not,
不如说说你今天为什么来这里
why don't you tell me what brings you here?
我来这里是因为无论我做什么
I'm here because no matter what I do,
都没有人会尊重我
nobody respects me.
杰西卡  我们得谈谈
Jessica, we need to talk.
确实
We do.
如果你希望我道歉...
But if you're looking for an apology--
我不是来这里让你道歉的
I'm not here for an apology.
我是来说我正在等布莱顿・古尔德律所
I'm here to tell you that I'm expecting a job offer
给我工作邀请
from Bratton Gould.
是你等...
You're expecting one...
还是你主动去找
or you went looking for one?
-这重要吗  -对我而言很重要
- Does it matter? - It does to me.
那你该知道我本来拒绝了一份工作
Then you should know, I was offered a job, I turned it down,
在你清楚表示你并不尊重我之前
and it was going to stay turned down
我都没有打算
until you made it crystal clear
接受这份工作
that you don't respect me.
我清楚表示的是  做主的人是我
What I made clear is that I call the shots,
如果你无法理解这对你的长远帮助...
and if you don't see how that helps you in the long run--
去他的长远
Screw the long run!
他们现在就要升我为合伙人
They're going to make me a partner now.
你根本不打算支持我
You won't even go to bat for me.
我告诉你  哈维
You know what, Harvey?
我快受够了你的那些关于我
I'm about done with your little song and dance
没有支持你的说法了
about how I don't have your back.
我从那个收发室把你挑出来
I picked you out of the goddamn mail room,
你所有的机会都是我给你的
and I've given you every opportunity you ever had.
这就是个错误
This was a mistake.
什么错误
What was a mistake?
我来这是给你个机会
I came here to give you a chance
让你来说服我别离开
to talk me out of leaving,
但是等合约来了的话  就太晚了
but when this offer comes in, it's too late.
出于好奇的问一句
Just out of curiosity,
你想让我做什么
what would you have me do?
你当然知道我想让你做什么
You know what the hell I'd have you do.
哈维  你的天赋比公司里
Harvey, you have more raw talent
百分之九十九的合伙人都高
than 99% of the partners in this firm,
但是我不会因为威胁就给你升职
but I'm not going to give you a promotion based on a threat.
等你准备好了  你就能得到
You'll get one when you're ready.
如果这些对于你来说还不够
And if that's not good enough for you...
那我祝你在布莱顿・古尔德一切顺利
then I wish you luck at Bratton Gould.
那就当我正式通知你了
Then consider this my official notice.
路易  我们刚才花了四十分钟
Louis, we spent the last 40 minutes going over
探讨了从你出生开始
every person who has shown you disrespect
每一个不尊重过你的人
since the day you were born.
你在开玩笑吗  我刚刚开始
You kidding? I'm just getting started.
尽管如此
Be that as it may,
如果我问你
if I ask you the one person
你最渴望哪个人的尊重
whose respect you crave the most,
那会是谁
who would it be?
不要思考  告诉我你脑海中闪现出来的
Don't dwell on it. Just say the first name
第一个名字
that pops into your head.
哈维・斯佩克特
Harvey Specter.
很好  他什么样
Good. What's he like?
他就像马龙・白兰度和超人的合体
He's like a cross between Marlon Brando and Superman.
怎么了
What?
我只是在想象这个形象
I'm just picturing.
这个哈维  他是你朋友吗
This Harvey, is he a friend?
他是我最好的朋友
He's my best friend.
他也认为你是他最好的朋友吗
Would he describe you as his best friend?
你这是什么意思
What the--what the fu-- is that supposed to mean?
-路易...  -你个混蛋
- Louis-- - You son of a bitch.
你是在暗示我没有他好吗
Are you implying that I'm not as good as him?
我没有用吗
That I'm worthless?
那你应该知道  你这个本该是犹太人的纳粹
Well you know what, you Nazi supposed Jew,
我不需要听你说这些
I don't need to take that from you.
我要离开这
I'm goddamn out of here!
这太好了  路易
Louis, this is wonderful.
你到底在说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
大多数人要花很多年才能显露真实的自己
Most people take years to reveal their true selves.
但是你  你就像没有皮肤的人
But you, you are like a man without skin.
我可以看透你
I can see right through you.
这太棒了
This is fantastic.
这怎么就棒了呢
How the hell is this fantastic?
因为我可以帮你
Because I can help you.
你的不尊重感是内在的
Your feelings of disrespect are internal,
你把这个感觉投射到你面前的人身上
and you project them onto the people in front of you,
而在你的生活中
and in your life,
被你投射这种感觉的人就会以不尊重你为回应
those people throw that disrespect back at you.
我不会这样对你
Well, I'm not going to do that to you.
我会陪在你身边
I'm going to be here for you.
这听起来就是胡扯
That sounds like a load of crap.
听我说
Listen to me.
如果你一直这样对待别人的话
If you keep treating the people in your life like this,
你只会把他们推远
you're going to push them away.
你知道吗  医生
You know what, doc?
杰西卡逼我来这里的  我做了
Jessica made me come here, and I did.
现在我来过了  也清楚的证明了
And now that I have, it's crystal clear
我根本不需要心理医生
the last thing I need in the world is therapy.
路易  冷静下来  你要把地毯走出洞了
Louis, calm down, you're wearing a hole in the carpet.
抱歉  唐娜  哈维说要开个紧急会议
Well, I'm sorry, Donna, Harvey called an emergency meeting.
你指望我怎么做
What do you expect?
我指望你控制一下自己
I expect a little self-control.
很好  你到了
Good, you're here.
格蕾琴说等不及了  发生什么事了
Gretchen said it couldn't wait--what's going on?
我有个行动要执行  但是在我执行之前
I've got a move I want to make, but before I do,
我想要大家投票表决一下
I want to put it to a vote.
-什么样的行动  -很大的
- What kind of move? - A big one.
哈维  这个和你与亚历克斯和迈克之间的
Harvey, does this have something to do with the fight
争吵有关系吗
between you, Alex, and Mike?
有  我有理由相信
Yes, and I have reason to believe
这场争吵并没有完
that fight's not over.
哈维  发生了什么
Harvey, what's going on?
亚历克斯被人握住了把柄
Alex has a gun to his head,
如果我什么都不做的话
and if I don't do something about it,
他就有大麻烦了
he's going to be in some deep shit.
我有个办法
I have a way out of it,
但是会有一些后果
but there's going to be some consequences.
-对谁  -对迈克
- For who? - For Mike.
哈维  还有别的办法吗
Harvey, is there any other way out of this mess?
如果有的话  我不会站在这了
If there were, I wouldn't be standing here.
那告诉我们你想要做什么
Then tell us what you want to do,
长痛不如短痛
and let's get this over with.
别告诉我这是一年前那个你提过的
Don't tell me this is the "Two partners for the price of one"
一份代价两个合伙人的提议
idea you pitched me a year ago?
是的  但是哈维・斯佩克特
It is, but Harvey Specter
和我们有过的律师都不一样
isn't like any lawyer we've ever had.
他最好是这样
Well, he's better not be,
既然他有勇气要出这种天价
if he has the balls to ask for the moon and stars like this.
问题是  我已经给世达律师事务所的人
Look, the problem is, I already have an offer out
发出邀约了
to a hotshot at Skadden.
那如果他还没答应
And if he hasn't already said yes,
他还等些什么呢
what the hell is he waiting for?
我告诉你为什么  他害怕他不应付不了这里
I'll tell you what: he's afraid he can't hack it here,
或者是利用我们来得到更好的邀约
or he's using us to get a better offer.
不管怎样  哈维和我都是更好的选择
Either way, Harvey and I are a better choice.
好了  亚历克斯
All right, Alex.
看起来你们俩确实计划得不错
It looks like you two guys have your shit together.
但是有个问题
But here's the thing:
我发出了邀约  你们拒绝我
I pull this offer, and your guy says no,
我就什么都不剩了
I'm left here with nothing but my dick in my hand.
所以你现在告诉我你保证他会同意
So you tell right now you guarantee that he says yes.
你以为我不知道你想要什么吗
You think I didn't know you were going to demand that?
我已经和他谈过了
I already talked to him about it.
他答应我了
He gave me his word.
好  看来我要有两位新合伙人了
Okay, looks like I have two new partners.
但是  亚历克斯
But Alex...
如果事情黄了  那就是你的责任
this thing goes south, it's your ass that's on the line.
你在喝咖啡吗
So you're having a good coffee?
我们现在十一点都干这个了吗
Is that what we're doing with our 11:00s now?
路易
Louis.
你到底有什么问题
What the hell is your problem?
我的问题是我发现你挪了我的出庭日期
My problem is I found out you moved my court dates,
所以你怎么不去告诉你的工作丈夫
so why don't you go tell your work husband
如果他觉得我会忘了这个
if he thinks I'm going to forget about this,
那他就是疯了
he's got another thing coming.
你知道吗  路易
You know what, Louis?
为什么你不亲自告诉他呢
Why don't you go tell him yourself?
但是你最好快点  因为周一之后
But you better hurry, because as of Monday,
哈维就不在这上班了
Harvey doesn't work here anymore.
-什么  -你听到我说的了
- What? - You heard me.
哈维要走了  我的生活一团糟
Harvey's leaving, my life is a mess,
就我而言  这都怪你
and as far as I'm concerned, that's on you.
我  你说我是什么意思
Me? What do you mean, me?
如果你不明白我为什么说是你
If you can't figure out what I mean by that,
那你也许是个很好的初级合伙人
then you may be a good junior partner,
但是你人生的路还有很长一段要走
but you got a long way to go as a human being.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
你为什么问我来这做什么
What do you mean, what am I doing here?
你想要阴谋  我找到了
You wanted a conspiracy, I got you one.
我不想要你的任何东西  我还要说
I don't want anything from you, and for the record,
而且我一开始就不该相信你
I was a fool to think I could trust you in the first place.
安妮塔  我不懂你在说些什么
Anita, I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
别在这装傻了
Don't play dumb with me.
皮尔逊-斯佩克特律师事务所不只为马斯特森辩护
Pearson Specter doesn't just represent Masterson;
你还为改造公司辩护
you also represent Reform Corp.
这就意味着因为你违反了保密特权
Which means anything I get from you is tainted
你给我的一切都被玷污了
because you broke privilege.
该死  哈维肯定是刚刚签的
Goddamn it, Harvey must have just signed them.
所以你的意思是
So what you're saying is,
哈维一开始就没同意这件事吗
Harvey was never on board with this in the first place?
安妮塔  你还可以接这个案子  好吗
Anita, you can still take this case, all right?
你只要说你拿到这些证据...
You just say you received the evidence--
匿名的吗  我不这样认为  迈克
Anonymously? I don't think so, Mike.
还有一件事
And one more thing:
下次你想把我带入一场
the next time you're looking to involve me
和哈维・斯佩克特的战争中
in a war with Harvey Specter,
找别人去吧
go to someone else.
杰西卡  我听说了哈维的事
Jessica, I heard about Harvey.
路易  他做出了他的决定
Louis, he made his choice.
那不是我想要的那个选择
It's not the choice that I wanted,
但是我们只能接受
but we're just going to have to deal with it.
现在  如果你不介意的话
Now, if you don't mind...
事实上  我很介意
Well, actually, I do mind.
杰西卡  整件事都是我的错
Jessica, this whole thing was my fault.
是我让他陷入了不得不离开的境地  你知道的
I put him in a position where he had to leave, and you know it.
路易  你这样很伟大  但是...
Louis, that's big of you, but--
没有但是
But nothing.
利普希茨医生说当人不尊重自己
Doctor Lipschitz said when you don't respect yourself,
就会潜意识寻找别人不尊重他的迹象
you go looking for signs of disrespect in others,
我当上初级合伙人的方法...
and the way I got to junior partner...
让我无法因此尊重我自己
I don't respect myself for that.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我是说如果导致他离开的原因是因为
I'm saying if it was my pride in refusing to admit
我的骄傲让我拒绝承认他是对的  而我是错的
that he was right and I was wrong that caused him to go,
我不会原谅自己
I won't be able to forgive myself.
所以请不要让他走
So please, do not let him go.
-路易  -怎么了
- Louis? - Yeah.
你之前说的是认真的吗
Did you mean what you said the other day?
关于律师们需要规范
About the associates needing guidance and discipline?
实话实说  我当时没那么想
To tell you the truth, I didn't at the time.
但现在是的  他们需要规范
But yes, they do.
作为律所的最新合伙人
Then as the firm's newest partner,
你愿意正式接管这些律师吗
how would you like to officially be in charge of the associates?
乐意之至
I'd like that very much.
那就好好待他们
Treat them well.
我会的
I will.
你是来告别的吗
Did you come here to say good-bye?
我以为咱们已经说过再见了
Because I think we already did that.
不  哈维
No, Harvey.
我来告诉你我做了
I came here to let you know that I did what
一开始就该做的事
I should have done in the first place.
什么意思
And what exactly does that mean?
我去见了丹尼尔  跟他说
It means I went to see Daniel, and I told him
如果我们的下任初级合伙人不是你
if the next person we promote to junior partner isn't you,
我就走
I'm leaving.
你为了我这样做
You did that for me?
有时目光长远
Sometimes playing the long game means understanding
意味着想明白你最终想要的队友是谁
who you want to be teammates with in the long run,
而我希望我最终的队友
and the person I want to be teammates with in the long run
是你
is you.
但愿现在还为时不晚  哈维
I hope I'm not too late, Harvey,
但如果太迟了
but if I am,
我也真的希望你在布莱顿・古尔德一切顺利
I really do wish you luck at Bratton Gould.
哈维  亚历克斯・威廉姆斯刚打电话了
Harvey, Alex Williams just called.
木已成舟  无法反悔
Says it's a done deal.
但我要说  我本愿意跟你一块儿去
For the record, I would have gone with you.
我也要说  我当初应该问你一句的
For the record, I should have asked you first.
-喂  -利普希茨医生
- Hello? - Dr. Lipschitz,
我是路易・利特
it's Louis Litt.
你是对的
Listen, you were right.
我的确需要一个不会被我推开的人
I do need someone who isn't going to let me push them away.
很高兴听到你这么说  路易
I'm very happy to hear that, Louis.
你觉得一周五天会不会太多了
Do you think five days a week is too much?
不如这周一先预约一次
Why don't we just start with an appointment on Monday
之后再看
and go from there?
好的
Sounds good.
你什么毛病
What the hell is wrong with you?
我好着呢
Nothing's wrong with me.
我叫你把它扔了
I ordered you to drop this thing.
然而你没有  那我就想法子让你扔掉
You didn't, so I figured out a way to make you drop it.
你认为签下改造公司
You think signing Reform Corp.
能解决问题吗  你真是脑子进水了
Is going to make this go away, you're out of your mind.
如果你真那么觉得
And if you think that's true,
你现在就不会站在这里
you wouldn't be in my face right now.
哈维  他们压榨早该恢复
Harvey, they are lining their pockets on the backs
自由身的人们来中饱私囊
of people who should have gone free years ago,
你是任由他们逃脱法律的制裁
and you're letting them get away with it.
我是他们的律师  不是检察官
I'm their lawyer. I'm not a prosecutor.
亚历克斯・威廉姆斯到底有你什么把柄
What the fu-- does Alex Williams have on you, huh?
没人有我的把柄
Nobody has anything on me.
那你为什么要这么做
Then why the hell are you doing this?
因为肯定不是为了钱
'Cause there's no way it's for the money.
你不明白
You don't understand.
那我告诉你我明白什么
I'll tell you what I do understand.
你欠他人情  而他们手里有他的把柄
You owe him something, and they have something on him,
如果我都能想出来  你认为
and if I can figure that out, how long do you think
事情败露还需要多久
it's gonna take before whatever it is gets out anyway?
听我说
You listen to me.
如果咱们平时能多互相支持对方
If you ever valued the times
你就能理解我为什么这么做了
that we've had each other's backs, you'll have mine now,
我跟你说了  我现在需要这个
because I'm telling you, I need it.
那就告诉我到底怎么回事
Then tell me what's going on.
恕难告知  因为我没法相信你
I'm not going to do that, because I can't trust you.
我这么跟你说吧  你的任何看起来
But I'll tell you this: You lift a finger to do something
都像还在办这个案子的小举动
that even looks like you're making another move on this case,
哪怕只是打给奥斯卡・雷耶斯
I don't care if you're calling Oscar Reyes
祝他生日快乐  你都会被解雇
to wish him a happy birthday, you're fired.
你有一晚上的时间
So why don't you take the night
来考虑你是否足够相信我
and decide if you trust me enough
留下  还是走人
to keep working here or not.
来看你的新办公室吗
You here to check out your new office?
已经准备好了
Because it's ready.
亚历克斯  我决定留在皮尔逊・哈德曼
Alex, I'm staying at Pearson Hardman.
什么  咱们已经说好了
What? We had a deal.
我知道  但是我想到了
I know that, but then I realized
杰西卡是家人  没有职位值得我放弃她
Jessica's family, and no title is worth giving that up.
我不管你什么想法
I don't care what you realized.
我告诉汤米・布莱顿你一定会签名
I told Tommy Bratton you'd sign on the dotted line.
他为了我拒绝了世达的一个红人
He pulled an offer to that hotshot from Skadden for me.
我知道你很难办
I know this puts you in a bad spot.
难办  你站在我面前
Bad spot? You stood in front of me,
许下你的狗屁承诺  我还满怀希望
gave me your goddamn word, and I banked on that,
我才不管你突然顿悟了什么
so I don't care what kind of come-to-Jesus moment
你的口头协议是有法律效用的
you think you had, that shit is legally binding.
如果你非得这样  那随便你
If you want to try to enforce that, go right ahead,
但你觉得如果一个律所
but what does it say to the world
为了让一个律师留下就要告人家
when a firm has to sue a lawyer
世人会怎么看
just to get him to come there?
如果我说我不再相信你呢
What's it say when I can't trust you anymore?
亚历克斯  你不需要我才能成为合伙人
Alex, you don't need me to make partner.
也许是吧  但你这样做太混蛋了
Maybe I don't, but this is some bullshit.
我不反对
I'm not saying it's not.
我知道现在我说什么都无济于事
And I know right now, my word means nothing,
但我答应你
but I promise you,
如果哪天你需要帮助
someday you're going to need help with something,
不管是什么  我都会尽全力帮你
and no matter what it is, I'll be there for you.
我欠你的
I owe you one.
随便你怎么样
And you can let it go or not,
但我诚恳地告诉你
but I'm telling you, man to man,
我必须这么做
this is something I have to do.
好  哈维  这事就这么过去了
Okay, Harvey, I'll let it go,
但你还欠我一个人情
but you do owe me one,
我需要的时候会兑现的
and someday I'm going to come calling.
哈维  我知道你想帮亚历克斯
Harvey, I know you want to help Alex,
但如果要以失去迈克为代价
but if it means losing Mike, then I have to ask,
真的值得吗
is it worth it?
迈克为你进了监狱
Mike went to prison for you.
我知道  唐娜
I know that, Donna.
哈维  亚历克斯做了什么
Harvey, what did Alex do?
你欠他这么大人情
Why do you owe him?
亚历克斯
Alex.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
有些话要跟你说清楚
I'm here to come clean to you.
哈维知道你过来吗
Does Harvey know you're here?
不知道  事实上他叫我不要找你
No--in fact, he told me not to talk to you at all,
但你有权知道真相...
but you have a right to know the truth, and...
我已经厌烦被这件事威胁了
I'm tired of having this whole thing hanging over my head.
进来说吧
Come on in.
亚历克斯告诉布莱顿我不去了之后
After Alex told Bratton that I wasn't coming,
公司把他贬的一无是处
he was nothing.
交给他毫无胜算的案子
They gave him unwinnable cases
还让他每天工作10小时以上
and worked him 90 hours a week
直到有一天  布莱顿告诉他
until one day, Bratton came to him
有一个办法挽回
and said there was a way back.
他需要做的就是
All he had to do was take on
接下马斯特森建筑公司的委托
Masterson Construction as a client.
-是的  -他答应了
- Exactly. - And he said yes.
我当然同意了
Of course I said yes.
没什么危险
There were no red flags.
犯人工作的弃权书只是一些生意上的事
The waiver that put inmates to work was just smart business.
表面上看都是合法的
On the surface, everything was legit.
那你是怎么发现那不合法的
So how'd you figure out it wasn't?
一天我在布伦斯维克监狱
One day, I was at Brunswick,
警卫递给我一张纸条
and a guard gave me a letter.
上面写着有犯人在工地上死了
It said an inmate had died on the job site,
但事情被挡下来了
and that it was being covered up.
我猜猜  你告诉了马斯特森的首席执行官
Let me guess: you took it to Pat Kreuger,
派特・克鲁格
Masterson's CEO,
他说会着手调查
and he said that he'd look into it.
两周后  那个警卫被犯人杀了
Two weeks later, that guard was murdered by an inmate.
天呐
Holy shit.
那时候他才知道马斯特森建筑公司
And that's when he knew Masterson and Reform Corp.
和改造公司一开始就密谋好了
had been colluding from the start.
然后他怎么做的
So what did he do?
他去找了管理合伙人
He went to his managing partner,
汤米・布莱顿说这不是两党勾结
and Tommy Bratton said it wasn't collusion between two parties.
而是三党勾结
It was collusion between three parties.
他们把我的津贴和关键日期都联系到一起
They tied all my bonuses to all the key dates...
-放弃书  -建筑的开始
- The waiver... - The start of construction...
-警卫的死  -看起来都像
- The guard's death... - It looked like
我精心策划的这整起事件
I orchestrated the whole damn thing.
所以你掩盖了谋杀的事实
So you covered up a murder?
我没有证据
I had no proof of anything.
我有妻女  而我又脱不了干系
I had a wife and daughter, and it looked like I was in on it.
哈维  这太可怕了  但与你无关
Harvey, that's horrible, but this isn't on you.
亚历克斯可以打匿名举报电话啊
Alex still could've made a call anonymously.
如果你发现迈克是个骗子你也会打的
And so could you when you found out Mike was a fraud.
你不是罪犯  但你的手也不干净了
You didn't have to be a party to a crime, but you were.
他的罪不是谋杀
That crime wasn't a murder.
你听我说了吗  唐娜  他们有他的把柄
Did you hear me, Donna? They had him.
我有妻子有女儿  而他们陷害我
I had a wife and daughter, and they set me up.
我能怎么办
What was I supposed to do?
迈克  我恨这些人
Mike, I hate these people.
他们就该下地狱
They deserve to go away for what they did,
我日日夜夜都希望
and every morning when I woke up and every night
让他们从世界上消失
when I went to sleep, I wanted to make that happen,
但我没有  原因只有一个
but I didn't, for one reason:
我不想让女儿失去父亲
I didn't want my daughter to grow up without a father,
如果你还穷追不舍的话
and if you pursue this,
我没有办法不卷入这场阴谋
there's no way I don't get caught up in it.
-你并不确定  -不  我确定
- You don't know that. - Yes, I do.
布莱顿不放过我们的客户
When Bratton came after our clients,
亚历克斯签下声明揽下全责
Alex signed a declaration saying he took full responsibility.
哈维  如果你想让迈克就这么过去
Harvey, if you're asking Mike to let this thing go...
我不知道我能不能做到
I don't know if I can do that.
我没有让你放下
I'm not asking you to let it go.
而是告诉你如果你不放下会发生什么
I'm telling you what will happen if you don't.